In this video and in
在这段视频
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
the video after this one, I
以及下一段视频中
wanna tell you about some of
我想告诉你一些关于
the practical tricks for making gradient descent work well.
梯度下降运算中的实用技巧
In this video, I want to tell you about an idea called feature skill.
在这段视频中 我会告诉你一个称为特征缩放 (feature scaling) 的方法
Here's the idea.
这个方法如下
If you have a problem where you
如果你有一个机器学习问题
have multiple features, if you
这个问题有多个特征
make sure that the features
如果你能确保这些特征
are on a similar scale, by
都处在一个相近的范围
which I mean make sure that
我的意思是确保
the different features take on
不同特征的取值
similar ranges of values,
在相近的范围内
then gradient descents can converge more quickly.
这样梯度下降法就能更快地收敛
Concretely let's say you
具体地说
have a problem with two features
假如你有一个具有两个特征的问题
where X1 is the size
其中 x1 是房屋面积大小
of house and takes on values
它的取值
between say zero to two thousand
在0到2000之间
and two is the number
x2 是卧室的数量
of bedrooms, and maybe that takes
可能这个值
on values between one and five.
取值范围在1到5之间
If you plot the contours of
如果你画出代价函数
the cos function J of theta,
J(θ) 的轮廓图
then the contours may look
那么这个轮廓看起来
like this, where, let's see,
应该是像这样的
J of theta is a function
J(θ) 是一个关于
of parameters theta zero, theta one and theta two.
参数 θ0 θ1 和 θ2 的函数
I'm going to ignore theta zero,
但我要忽略 θ0
so let's about theta 0
所以暂时不考虑 θ0
and pretend as a function of
并假想一个函数的变量
only theta 1 and theta
只有 θ1 和 θ2
2, but if x1 can take on
但如果 x1 的取值范围
them, you know, much larger range
远远大于 x2 的取值范围的话
of values and x2 It turns
那么最终画出来的
out that the contours of the
代价函数 J(θ) 的轮廓图
cause function J of theta
就会呈现出这样一种
can take on this very
非常偏斜
very skewed elliptical shape, except
并且椭圆的形状
that with the so 2000 to
2000 和 5的比例
5 ratio, it can be even more secure.
会让这个椭圆更加瘦长
So, this is very, very tall
所以 这是一个又瘦又高的
and skinny ellipses, or these
椭圆形轮廓图
very tall skinny ovals, can form
就是这些非常高大细长的椭圆形
the contours of the cause function J of theta.
构成了代价函数 J(θ)
And if you run gradient descents
而如果你用这个代价函数
on this cos-function, your
来运行梯度下降的话
gradients may end up
你要得到梯度值 最终可能
taking a long time and
需要花很长一段时间
can oscillate back and forth
并且可能会来回波动
and take a long time before it
然后会经过很长时间
can finally find its way to the global minimum.
最终才收敛到全局最小值
In fact, you can imagine if these
事实上 你可以想像 如果这些
contours are exaggerated even
轮廓再被放大一些的话
more when you draw incredibly
如果你画的再夸张一些
skinny, tall skinny contours,
把它画的更细更长
and it can be even more extreme
那么可能情况会更糟糕
than, then, gradient descent
梯度下降的过程
just have a much
可能更加缓慢
harder time taking it's way,
需要花更长的时间
meandering around, it can take
反复来回振荡
a long time to find this way to the global minimum.
最终才找到一条正确通往全局最小值的路
In these settings, a useful
在这样的情况下
thing to do is to scale the features.
一种有效的方法是进行特征缩放(feature scaling)
Concretely if you instead
具体来说
define the feature X
把特征 x 定义为
one to be the size of
房子的面积大小
the house divided by two thousand,
除以2000的话
and define X two to be
并且把 x2 定义为
maybe the number of bedrooms divided
卧室的数量除以5
by five, then the
那么这样的话
count well as of the
表示代价函数 J(θ)
cost function J can become
的轮廓图的形状
much more, much less
就会变得偏移没那么严重
skewed so the contours may look more like circles.
可能看起来更圆一些了
And if you run gradient
如果你用这样的代价函数
descent on a cost function like
来执行梯度下降的话
this, then gradient descent,
那么 梯度下降算法
you can show mathematically, you can
你可以从数学上来证明
find a much more direct path
梯度下降算法 就会找到一条
to the global minimum rather than taking
更捷径的路径通向全局最小
a much more convoluted path
而不是像刚才那样
where you're sort of trying to
沿着一条让人摸不着头脑的路径
follow a much more complicated
一条复杂得多的轨迹
trajectory to get to the global minimum.
来找到全局最小值
So, by scaling the features so
因此 通过特征缩放
that there are, the consumer ranges of values.
通过"消耗掉"这些值的范围
In this example, we end up
在这个例子中
with both features, X one
我们最终得到的两个特征
and X two, between zero and one.
x1 和 x2 都在0和1之间
You can wind up with an implementation of gradient descent.
这样你得到的梯度下降算法
They can convert much faster.
就会更快地收敛
More generally, when we're performing
更一般地
feature scaling, what we often
我们执行特征缩放时 也就是我们经常
want to do is get every
我们通常的目的是
feature into approximately a  -1
将特征的取值约束到
to +1 range and concretely,
-1 到 +1 的范围内
your feature x0 is always equal to 1.
你的特征 x0 是总是等于1
So, that's already in that range,
因此 这已经是在这个范围内
but you may end up dividing
但对其他的特征
other features by different numbers
你可能需要通过除以不同的数
to get them to this range.
来让它们处于同一范围内
The numbers -1 and +1 aren't too important.
-1 和 +1 这两个数字并不是太重要
So, if you have a feature,
所以 如果你有一个特征
x1 that winds up
x1 它的取值
being between zero and three, that's not a problem.
在0和3之间 这没问题
If you end up having a different
如果你有另外一个特征
feature that winds being
取值在-2 到 +0.5之间
between -2 and  + 0.5,
这也没什么关系
again, this is close enough
这也非常接近
to minus one and plus one
-1 到 +1的范围
that, you know, that's fine, and that's fine.
这些都可以
It's only if you have a
但如果你有另一个特征
different feature, say X 3
比如叫  x3
that is between, that
假如它的范围
ranges from -100 tp +100
在 -100 到 +100之间
, then, this is a
那么 这个范围
very different values than minus 1 and plus 1.
跟-1到+1就有很大不同了
So, this might be a
所以 这可能是一个
less well-skilled feature and similarly,
不那么好的特征
if your features take on a
类似地 如果你的特征在一个
very, very small range of
非常非常小的范围内
values so if X 4
比如另外一个特征
takes on values between minus
x4 它的范围在
0.0001 and positive 0.0001, then
0.0001和+0.0001之间 那么
again this takes on a
这同样是一个
much smaller range of values
比-1到+1小得多的范围
than the minus one to plus one range.
And again I would consider this feature poorly scaled.
因此 我同样会认为这个特征也不太好
So you want the range of
所以 可能你认可的范围
values, you know, can be
也许可以大于
bigger than plus or smaller
或者小于 -1 到 +1
than plus one, but just
但是也别太大
not much bigger, like plus
只要大得不多就可以接受
100 here, or too
比如 +100
much smaller like 0.00 one over there.
或者也别太小 比如这里的0.001
Different people have different rules of thumb.
不同的人有不同的经验
But the one that I use is
但是我一般是这么考虑的
that if a feature takes
如果一个特征是在
on the range of values from
-3 到 +3 的范围内
say minus three the plus
那么你应该认为
3 how you should think that should
这个范围是可以接受的
be just fine, but maybe
但如果这个范围
it takes on much larger values
大于了 -3 到 +3 的范围
than plus 3 or minus 3
我可能就要开始注意了
unless not to worry and if
如果它的取值
it takes on values from say minus one-third to one-third.
在-1/3 到+1/3的话
You know, I think that's fine
我觉得 还不错 可以接受
too or 0 to one-third or minus one-third to 0.
或者是0到1/3 或-1/3到0
I guess that's typical range of value sector 0 okay.
这些典型的范围 我都认为是可以接受的
But it will take on a
但如果特征的范围
much tinier range of values
取得很小的话
like x4 here than gain on mine not to worry.
比如像这里的 x4 你就要开始考虑进行特征缩放了
So, the take-home message
因此 总的来说
is don't worry if your
不用过于担心
features are not exactly on
你的特征是否在完全
the same scale or exactly in the same range of values.
相同的范围或区间内
But so long as they're all
但是只要他们都
close enough to this gradient descent it should work okay.
只要它们足够接近的话 梯度下降法就会正常地工作
In addition to dividing by
除了在特征缩放中
so that the maximum value when
将特征除以最大值以外
performing feature scaling sometimes
有时候我们也会进行一个
people will also do what's called mean normalization.
称为均值归一化的工作(mean normalization)
And what I mean by
我的意思是这样的
that is that you want
如果你有一个特征 xi
to take a feature Xi and replace
你就用 xi - μi 来替换
it with Xi minus new i
通过这样做 让你的特征值
to make your features have approximately 0 mean.
具有为0的平均值
And obviously we want
很明显 我们不需要
to apply this to the future
把这一步应用到
x zero, because the future
x0中
x zero is always equal to
因为 x0 总是等于1的
one, so it cannot have an
所以它不可能有
average value of zero.
为0的的平均值
But it concretely for other
但是
features if the range
对其他的特征来说
of sizes of the house
比如房子的大小
takes on values between 0
取值介于0到2000
to 2000 and if you know,
并且假如
the average size of a
房子面积
house is equal to
的平均值
1000 then you might
是等于1000的
use this formula.
那么你可以用这个公式
Size, set the feature
将 x1 的值变为
X1 to the size minus
x1 减去平均值 μ1
the average value divided by 2000
再除以2000
and similarly, on average
类似地
if your houses have
如果你的房子有
one to five bedrooms and if
五间卧室
on average a house has
并且平均一套房子有
two bedrooms then you might
两间卧室 那么你可以
use this formula to mean
使用这个公式
normalize your second feature x2.
来归一化你的第二个特征 x2
In both of these cases, you
在这两种情况下
therefore wind up with features x1 and x2.
你可以算出新的特征 x1 和 x2
They can take on values roughly
这样它们的范围
between minus .5 and positive .5.
可以在-0.5和+0.5之间
Exactly not true - X2
当然这肯定不对
can actually be slightly larger than .5 but, close enough.
x2的值实际上肯定会大于0.5 但很接近
And the more general rule is
更一般的规律是
that you might take a
你可以用这样的公式
feature X1 and replace
你可以用 (x1 - μ1)/S1
it with X1 minus mu1
来替换原来的特征 x1
over S1 where to
其中定义
define these terms mu1 is
μ1的意思是
the average value of x1
在训练集中
in the training sets
特征 x1 的平均值
and S1 is the
而 S1 是
range of values of that
该特征值的范围
feature and by range, I
我说的范围是指
mean let's say the maximum
最大值减去最小值
value minus the minimum
value or for those
或者学过
of you that understand the deviation
标准差的同学可以记住
of the variable is setting S1
也可以把 S1 设为
to be the standard deviation of the variable would be fine, too.
变量的标准差
But taking, you know, this max minus min would be fine.
但其实用最大值减最小值就可以了
And similarly for the second
类似地 对于第二个
feature, x2, you replace
特征 x2
x2 with this sort of
你也可以用同样的这个
subtract the mean of the feature
特征减去平均值
and divide it by the range
再除以范围 来替换原特征
of values meaning the max minus min.
范围的意思依然是最大值减最小值
And this sort of formula will
这类公式将
get your features, you know, maybe
把你的特征
not exactly, but maybe roughly
变成这样的范围
into these sorts of
也许不是完全这样
ranges, and by the
但大概是这样的范围
way, for those of you that
顺便提一下
are being super careful technically if
有些同学可能比较仔细
we're taking the range as max
如果我们用最大值减最小值
minus min this five here will actually become a four.
来表示范围的话 这里的5有可能应该是4
So if max is 5
如果最大值为5
minus 1 then the range of
那么减去最小值1
their own values is actually
这个范围值就是4
equal to 4, but all of these
但不管咋说 这些取值
are approximate and any value
都是非常近似的
that gets the features into
只要将特征转换为
anything close to these sorts of ranges will do fine.
相近似的范围 就都是可以的
And the feature scaling
特征缩放其实
doesn't have to be too exact,
并不需要太精确
in order to get gradient
只是为了让梯度下降
descent to run quite a lot faster.
能够运行得更快一点而已
So, now you know
好的 现在你知道了
about feature scaling and if
什么是特征缩放
you apply this simple trick, it
通过使用这个简单的方法
and make gradient descent run much
你可以将梯度下降的速度变得更快
faster and converge in a lot fewer other iterations.
让梯度下降收敛所需的循环次数更少
That was feature scaling.
这就是特征缩放
In the next video, I'll tell
在接下来的视频中
you about another trick to make
我将介绍另一种技巧来使梯度下降
gradient descent work well in practice.
在实践中工作地更好